David Govardhan great David do you want
a stud do you wanna ask your question
first I just had my students in a
foundations of education class I'm
teaching right now read understanding
the blue church and I gave them an
assignment it's actually their final
paper that requires them to evaluate
whether or not compulsory schooling
should have any role in helping us move
forward in a kind of post blue church
world and I was wondering if you're
familiar with Yvonne Ilic is D school in
society or if you had any thoughts that
all along the question of compulsory
schooling has the kind of foundational
element of the blue church my opinion I
think it all comes down to the question
of how we raise our kids and how we
bring them into collective since Nikki
thoughts
yeah and great you want muscular
questions I think it's in my mind if
mine can work in that same space I mean
you've hit I'm an educator you've hit
the teenagers and you said kids being
kids but you can apply that to his
question just being with those younger
primary school-aged children teaching
them this I mean how does that I have
access to be able to alter that game
very quickly at my high school just as a
matter of fact so I'm interested to hear
what you say
well I'm noticing in myself but I'm
gonna have to keep this into somewhat
academic forum because if I actually
allow myself to feel it directly the
amount of rage and anger I feel at the
the damage that has been done would be
difficult to contain so can I match yes
I have Fred Ivan Illich and I feel very
closely connected to the things that he
was talking about I think he hit the
nail on the head pretty well I kind of
wish we've done a better job so yes
absolutely I mean the the the yoking and
the training and the embodiment of the
causing of the people to separate
themselves from their own bodies and
their own sense of what is right wrong
and their own ability to actually
develop their own capacity to refine
their sense-making in the discernment on
the basis of who they are I mean that's
the thing that we just have lost so
enormous Lee is that everybody is a
singular event in the universe which
means infinitely subtle and infinitely
mysterious to themselves and everyone
else and that endeavor to yolk them to a
cookie cutter method Allah
is unbelievably harmful and so to
cultivate an individual their actual
unique capacity to perceive reality and
learn how they themselves understand how
to come into conformity with what is and
to respond to it in a fashion which is
actually effective is simply nothing
more or less than ethics so everything
that has been done thus far under the
heading of compulsory schooling has in
many ways been distinctly a
categorically unethical the most
monstrous way imaginable
even though perhaps the many ways
well-intentioned and by the way if you
know the history of Education in many
ways not so well intentioned so
compulsory schooling is an absolute
nonsense compulsory life well it turns
out that's just the way it is now you
actually do have to live you have to
develop you have to be in relationship
with experience and with other people
and with yourself and so ok let's figure
out how to support people and doing the
thing that they have to do anyway and
make it as natural and rich as possible
man if anything at all came out of this
it was a shift if it's a shift there I
would consider that to be the biggest
possible boon
[Music]
you